George Kleine Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
George Kleine Papers 1886-1946 1900-1930
MSS52274
Kleine, George
26,000 items
77 containers
30.6 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Film executive and businessman. Business records consisting of correspondence, financial and legal papers, newspaper clippings, printed matter, and other material relating primarily to Kleine's ventures in the early motion picture industry. Includes files relating to patent and distribution litigation, educational and European films, and to Kleine's business relations with Thomas A. Edison, Eastman Kodak Company, Motion Picture Patents Company, and Biograph Co.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Edison, Thomas A. (Thomas Alva), 1847-1931.; Kleine, George.
Organizations
Ambrosio (Firm); Biograph Company.; Cines (Firm); Eastman Kodak Company.; Eclipse (Firm); Essanay Film Manufacturing Co.; Famous Players-Lasky Corporation.; General Film Company.; Greater New York Film Rental Company.; Kalem Company.; Kleine (George) Collection (Library of Congress); Kleine Optical Company.; Motion Picture Patents Company.; Thomas A. Edison, Inc.; United Theatre Equipment Corporation.
Subjects
Motion picture industry--United States.; Motion pictures in education.; Motion pictures--Distribution.; Motion pictures--Europe.; Motion pictures--Patents.; Motion pictures--United States.
Occupations
Businessmen.; Executives.
Acquisition Information
The papers of George Kleine, film executive and businessman, were transferred to the Manuscript Division from the Motion Picture Division of the Library of Congress in 1967.
Additional Guides
In 1979 the Library published George Kleine, a Register of His Papers in the Library of Congress.
Transfers
Items have been transferred from the Manuscript Division to other custodial divisions of the Library. Some photographs and posters have been transferred to the Library's Prints and Photographs Division. Sheet music has been transferred to the Music Division. All transfers are identified in these divisions as part of the George Kleine Papers.
Related Material
Select papers from the George Kleine film collection are available in the Library's Moving Image Research Center, National Audio-Visual Conservation Center, and described at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsmi/eadmbrsmi.mi020002.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of George Kleine are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1863 Born, New York, N.Y.
1882 Graduated, City College of New York, New York, N.Y.
1896 Became involved in the motion picture business
1897 Incorporated the George Kleine Optical Co., Chicago, Ill.
1903 Began the importation of foreign films
1906 Established film rental and selling branches in the United States and Canada
1907 Founded, with Samuel Long and Frank J. Marion, the Kalem Co., and served as first president
1910 Published Catalog of Educational Moving Pictures. Chicago: Press of Bentley, Murray Sold his distributing exchanges to the General Film Co., served as vice president, 1910-1913, and president, 1916
1913 Imported the Italian film Quo Vadis? that became a model for future films
1916 With others formed the Kleine-Edison-Selig-Essanay Service
1917 Instituted a new film rental system
1920s Devoted much time to the development of a system for the distribution of educational films
1921 Produced the serial The Hope Diamond Mystery
1923 Moved to New York, N.Y.; became treasurer and chairman of the board of directors of Ritz-Carlton Pictures
1931, June 8 Died, New York, N.Y.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of George Kleine (1863-1931) span the years 1886-1946, with the bulk of the material dated between 1900 and 1930. The collection consists primarily of business records including correspondence, financial and legal papers, newspaper clippings, printed matter, and miscellaneous material generated by Kleine's various financial ventures in the motion picture industry. The papers are organized into three series: Subject File, Inventories and Lists, and Distribution File.
A variety of material in the Subject File documents the early history of the motion picture industry. There are patent papers for some of the first projection equipment, legal documents from court suits, and correspondence of major producers, distributors, and exhibitors.
The extent of Kleine's involvement in the industry is evident from files on corporations that comprise a large portion of the Subject File. In addition to papers relating to companies that Kleine either owned or was associated with, such as Kleine Optical Company, Kalem Company, and United Theatre Equipment Corporation, there are papers for Eastman Kodak Company, Biograph Company, Essanay Film Manufacturing Co., and Famous Players-Lasky Corporation.
Kleine's relationship with the Thomas A. Edison enterprises is documented in a file on Edison and in correspondence with Thomas A. Edison, Inc. Kleine made extensive use of Edison's “Conquest Film” series, which was especially designed for use in schools, churches, and civic organizations. Kleine was also a member with Thomas A. Edison, Inc., and other firms in the first motion picture trust, the Motion Picture Patents Company, and its distributing arm, the General Film Company, in which Kleine served as vice president and later president. There are substantial files for this venture. The papers also document the trust's fall from power following a suit against it by the Greater New York Film Rental Company. The particulars of this suit and other legal entanglements are detailed in files on litigation and Motion Picture Patents Company litigation.
Both the Subject File and Distribution File series document Kleine's efforts to establish a non-theatrical film distribution system. His aim to provide wholesome and instructional films is evident in the titles of subject files: “better and highbrow film movements,” non-theatrical films,” “educational films,” “educational distribution to universities,” and “educational institutions.” In correspondence with William H. Dudley, chief of the Bureau of Visual Instruction of the University of Wisconsin and organizer of the National Academy of Visual Instruction, Kleine discusses his proposals for ensuring the moral content of film subjects. In the Distribution File series is evidence of his system for distributing films to schools, churches, and community organizations through state universities.
The importation of foreign films consumed a significant part of Kleine's professional interests beginning in 1903. Kleine eventually became the largest importer of foreign films in the United States and Canada. In the Subject File is correspondence with foreign film companies such as Ambrosio (Societá Anonima Ambrosio), Cines (Societá Italiana Cines), and Eclipse (Société Générale des Cinématographers). Among the foreign films featured are The Last Days of Pompeii, Julius Caesar, and the spectacular motion picture, Quo Vadis? Kleine discontinued importing films after the start of World War I, but correspondence in the 1920s with Alfred Bourget, his representative in France, reveals a continuing interest in the subject.
Other topics in the collection that reflect on the early history of the film trade include files on censorship, copyright, prize fights, and World War I.
Though brief in size, the Inventories and Lists series and Distribution File series provide an overview of the most popular or sought-after film releases for the periods covered. Together with subject files on banks, branches, distribution, finances, and historical material, they give a detailed picture of the film distribution system for which Kleine is best known.
Arrangement of the Papers
The collection is arranged in three series:
Subject File, 1886-1946
Inventories and Lists, circa 1900-1945
Distribution File, 1920-1932
Container List
- Subject File, 1886-1946 (Box 1-67)
  Correspondence, financial and legal papers, clippings, printed matter, and miscellaneous material.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic, title of film production, name of organization, or person.
  - A. Film Co. See Container 2, Armstrong, W. W., and Leon Bories (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Hiram, 1908, 1926
  - Advertising
    - Classics series, 1913, 1929
    - Miscellaneous, 1913-1928
  - Aetna Life Insurance Co., 1922-1928
  - Airplanes and Wilbur Wright, 1909
  - Albion Cinema Supplies Co. and Royal Film Agency ( The Cossack Whip ), 1919-1922
  - All Star Feature Distributors See Container 33, same heading
  - Allen (Jule and Jay J.), 1919
  - Alliance Trading Co. (Guido Serra), 1919-1922
  - Altschuler, Modest, 1924
  - Amalgamated Film Exchange, 1909-1918, undated
  - Ambrosio (Societa Anonima Ambrosio), 1913-1920
  - American Motion Picture Corp., 1923-1924
  - American Red Cross, 1920
  - American Show Print Co., 1920-1928
  - Americanism Committee of the Motion Picture Industry of the United States, 1920
  - Amkino Corp. See Container 51, Russian educational films
  - Anne Boleyn, 1913
  - Ansbach Amusement Co., 1916-1919
  - Antony and Cleopatra, 1913-1928
  - The Apple-Tree Girl, 1917-1918
  - Applications, 1915-1916
  - “Archaeology and Moving Pictures,” by B. L. Ullman, Art and Archaeology, vol. 15, Apr. 1923, pp. 177-183
  - Arcus Ticket Co. See Container 59, same heading. (Box 2)
  - Armstrong, W. W., and Leon Bories (A. Film Co.), 1917-1923, (3 folders)
  - Art and the Motion Picture, by Carlyle Ellis (galley of article)
  - Art Sign Corp., 1918, 1920
  - Ashton, Rosalie, 1930
  - Associated First National Pictures of Michigan See Container 52, Scott, Harry
  - Authors' League of America, 1916
  - The Awakening of Ruth (Girl From the Sea), 1917
  - Banks
    - Branch banks (Boston, Mass.; Minneapolis, Minn.; Dallas, Tex.,etc.), 1920-1921
    - Canada (Vancouver), 1923-1924
    - Codes for cabling balances, 1924
    - Harriman National Bank, 1914-1920
    - London, England, 1920-1923
  - Barber, Frederick Arthur, 1928-1930
  - The Barber of Seville, 1913-1914
  - Barnaby Lee, 1916-1925
  - Bates, Frank, 1921-1923
  - Batigne, Rene, 1927, undated
  - Baumer Films, 1920-1923
  - Bausch & Lomb Optical Co., 1904, 1926 See also Container 59, same heading.
  - Beadell, Ben (Box 3)
  - Bech, Van Siclen and Co., 1919-1924, undated, (2 folders)
  - Beck, Arthur F. See Container 12, The Destroying Angel
  - Beggars on Horseback, 1924
  - Behind the Lines in Italy, 1918
  - Bell and Howell Co., 1927-1930
  - Bell, Nelson B.
  - Bell Pictures, 1930 See also Container 20, Exploitation and distribution
  - Ben Hur, 1913, 1923
  - Bergh, D. H.
    - 1915-1917, (4 folders)
    - 1918-1920, undated (Box 4)
  - Berman, Charles See Container 5, Cooper, Thomas S., and Charles Berman
  - Bermuda, 1915
  - Berri, Maude Lillian, 1916
  - Berst, J. A., 1914
  - Better and highbrow film movements, 1914-1923
  - Between Savage and Tiger, 1913-1914
  - Bickel, George, and Harry Watson, Jr., 1915-1922
  - Big Three Film Exchange, 1926
  - Biograph Co., 1914-1926
  - Birmingham (Ala.) Film Exchange, 1908-1909
  - A Blackjack Bargainer and In the Fog, 1921
  - Bloom, Sol, 1914-1916
  - Boetzel, Eric L. See Container 59, same heading
  - Bolster, Harold, 1917-1925
  - Boone University Library, 1921
  - Bories, Leon See Container 2, Armstrong, W. W., and Leon Bories
  - Bourget, Alfred See Container 23, France
  - Boy Scouts of America, 1921-1926
  - Bradenburgh, G. W., 1916
  - Brady, William A. See Container 38, National Association of Moving Picture Associations
  - Branches
    - Accounting, 1914-1916
    - Boston, Mass., 1918-1919
    - Closing, 1919-1924
    - Exchanges, 1915-1920
    - Interoffice, New York, N.Y., and Chicago, Ill., 1919-1921, undated, (4 folders)
    - Leases, 1909-1924 (Box 5)
    - Minneapolis, Minn., 1920
    - Offices, 1917
  - Brazelle, Charles Lander
  - Bromberg, Arthur C., 1924
  - The Brook, 1917
  - Brown of Harvard, 1917-1920
  - Brownell, John C. (Universal Film Manufacturing Co.), 1920
  - Buckwalter, H. H., 1924-1926
  - Bulkley, H. G. (Positype Corp. of America), 1924-1926
  - Burkan, Nathan, 1916
  - Burke, Billie, 1916
  - Burnet-Kuhn Advertising Co., 1917
  - Burroughs Adding Machine Co., 1917-1920
  - Busby, Frank M., 1908-1924
  - Café des Beaux-Arts, 1916
  - Calehuff, Charles A. See Container 60, same heading.
  - Calumet Film Exchange, 1909-1910
  - Canada
    - Bon Cinema Enrg.
    - Cooper, Thomas S., and Charles Berman, 1919-1920
  - Canadian Exhibitor Exchange, 1919
  - Canavan, the Man Who Had His Way, 1915
  - Capitol Machine Co., 1927
  - Carmen, Fletcher, 1929
  - Carter (Katherine F.), Inc. See Container 40, same heading
  - Cartoons and comedies, 1916
  - Castle Films
  - Catrow, H. G., 1921
  - Celebrated Players Film Corp., 1921 (Box 6)
  - Censorship
    - First, 1909
    - “Hays office,” 1916, undated
    - Connecticut, 1925
    - Kansas, 1915, 1919
    - New York, 1921-1922, 1927
    - Ohio, 1912-1927, (2 folders)
    - Pennsylvania, 1915-1929, (2 folders)
    - Washington, D.C., 1914, 1918
  - Central Bureau for Registered Addresses, 1929
  - Chadwick Pictures Corp., 1918-1920
  - Chaplain, Charles, 1918-1921
  - Chaplin Classics, 1922
  - Charles & Co., 1929-1930
  - Chicago Athletic Association, Chicago, Ill., 1926-1929
  - Chicago Film Exchange, Chicago, Ill. See Container 36, same heading
  - Chidnoff Studio
  - Choynski, Morris See Container 33, Wolf, Nathan, and Morris Choynski; and Container 36, same heading
  - Christian Register, 1929
  - Christie Comedy Co., 1925
  - Churchill, Thomas W., 1913-1916
  - Cifre, Joseph See Container 60, same heading
  - Cinema Exhibitors Association, 1916
  - Cines (Societa Italiana Cines) (Box 7)
    - 1911-July 1914, (6 folders)
    - Aug. 1914-1924, undated See also Container 49, Contracts with Cines and James W. Davidson of Canada, (4 folders) (Box 8)
  - Circular letters, 1917-1926, undated
  - Classical Journal, 1922, 1929
  - Clement-Mason Films See Container 28, Imperial Films
  - Clubs, 1900-1923
  - Cohan, George, 1930
  - Cohan & Harris, 1913, 1917
  - Cohen, Benjamin, 1929 See also Container 60, same heading.
  - Cohen, Harry J., 1929
  - Cole, Rex, 1929-1930
  - Collard, H. T. See Container 20, Film Service Bureau
  - College of the City of New York, New York, N.Y., 1926, 1928
  - The Colonel of the Red Huzzars, 1912
  - Commander Hotel, New York, N.Y., 1929
  - Commercial Cable Co., 1930
  - Community Motion Picture Bureau
    - Dallas, Tex., 1919-1920
    - New York, N.Y., 1919-1920
  - The Commuters, 1915-1925
  - Conquest Films, 1917-1928, undated
  - Consolidated Film Industries, 1924-1930
  - Consolidated Pictures and Photo Products Export Co., 1920
  - Contests and prizes, 1914
  - Contract and agreement forms
  - Contract memoranda file, 1919
  - Convention News, 1913 (Box 9)
  - Cool, Roy C., 1926
  - Cooney & Verhoeven, 1915-1916
  - Cooper, Douglas, 1914-1930
  - Cooper Thomas S. (General Film Co. [Canada]), 1919 See also Container 5, Cooper, Thomas S., and Charles Berman
  - Copyright
    - Canadian, 1924
    - Decisions, 1911-1926
    - Infringement, 1917, 1919, 1928
    - Legislation, 1912-1919
    - Litigation, 1912-1920
    - Quo Vadis?, 1911-1925
  - The Cossack Whip, 1916-1927
  - Costikyan, Kevork, 1925
  - Coufal, Joseph F., 1929 See also Container 60, same heading
  - Cox and Sons Co., 1929-1930
  - Craerin, R. G. (Strobridge Lithographing Co.), 1923 (Box 10)
  - Crandall, Ernest L.
  - Credit ratings, 1913-1928, (2 folders)
  - Credit reports, 1906-1912
  - Crescent Towel Supply Co., 1929
  - Criticism ( Quo Vadis? ), 1913, undated
  - Critics (motion picture and dramatic), 1911, 1920
  - Crosby W. C. See Container 40, same heading
  - Culver Military Academy, Culver, Ind., 1922
  - Curtis Publishing Co., 1928
  - The Customary Two Weeks, 1917
  - Cy Whitaker's Ward, 1917
  - Dacey, John, 1929
  - Datlowe, Samuel, 1929
  - Davidson (James W.) of Canada See Container 49, Contracts with Cines and James W. Davidson of Canada
  - Davis, Owen (stories), 1915-1925
  - Davis, Richard Harding, 1926
  - Dawson, Robert J., 1917-1918
  - Dearborn Independent, 1921
  - Decker, D. O., 1930
  - De Forest Phonofilms, 1924-1928, undated
  - Delforno, Henrietta (Mrs. Enrico Dente), 1914-1927, undated, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Deliverance
    - College reports, 1922-1925
    - Correspondence, 1919-1930
    - Financial records, 1919-1928, (2 folders)
  - Democracy, 1919-1921
  - Deposit system, 1917-1920 (Box 12)
  - Derr (A. C.) Co. See Container 21, same heading
  - Dessiz, Elizabeth Richey, 1928
  - The Destroying Angel (Arthur F. Beck), 1919-1923
  - DeVry Corp., 1920-1921
  - The Dinosaur and the Missing Link, 1924
  - Directors, 1913-1927, undated
  - Distribution
    - General, 1916-1928, undated
    - Plans, improvements, and methods, 1917, 1926
    - Reports, 1917, undated
    - State rights and percentages, 1920, undated
  - Dixie Film Co., 1921
  - Du Barry, 1913-1929
  - Dudley, William H., 1929-1930 See also Container 40, Dudley, William H., and F. W. Reynolds
  - Dupes, 1917
  - Dyer, Frank L., 1911, 1915
  - E & H Film Distributing Co., 1920 (Box 13)
  - Eastman Kodak Co.
    - General, 1908-1928
    - Eastman Teaching Films, 1929-1930, undated See also Container 26, Eastman Kodak Co.; and Container 50, Raw film stock
  - Eckhardt, Conrad See Container 60, same heading
  - Eclipse (Société Générale des Cinématographes) and Urban Trading Co., 1908-1915
  - Edengraph
    - General
      - 1907-1909, (2 folders)
      - 1910-1923, undated, (2 folders) (Box 14)
    - Equipment, 1910-1928
    - Minutes of meetings, Edengraph Manufacturing Co., 1907-1911
    - Patents
      - 1903-1928, (3 folders)
      - Printed diagrams and texts, 1897-1912 (Box 15)
    - Publicity, 1910-1911
    - Simplex, 1903-1929, (3 folders)
  - Edison, Thomas A.
    - Camera patent decision, 1902
    - Clippings, 1924, 1928
    - Correspondence, 1921, 1929
    - Dinners, 1911-1928
    - Edengraph See Container 43, Edison, Thomas A. (edengraph)
    - Kinetoscope projector model, 1901
    - Luncheon, 1924 (Box 16)
    - Memorabilia
  - Edison (Thomas A.), Inc.
    - 1915-Apr. 1918, (4 folders)
    - May 1918-1930, undated See also Container 35, A Message to Garcia; and Container 45, same heading, (6 folders) (Box 17)
  - Edison Institute, 1928-1930 (Box 18)
  - Edison Lamp Works See Container 60, Edison Lamp Works, General Electric Co.
  - Edison Manufacturing Co., 1902-1908
  - Edison Pioneers, 1923
  - Edison Studios, 1919-1920
  - Edmunds, W. O., 1910-1914
  - Edouarde, Carl, 1929
  - Educational and Motion Picture Entertainment Bureau See Container 40, Carter (Katherine F.), Inc. (Educational and Motion Picture Entertainment Bureau)
  - Educational distribution to universities, 1921-1928
  - Educational Film Bureau, 1921
  - Educational Film Magazine, 1921
  - Educational films, 1916, 1920-1930
  - Educational institutions, 1913-1930
  - Educational Screen, 1929
  - Edwards, C. S. (Kansas City Film Corp.), 1919-1925
  - Edwards, Herbert T. See Container 60, same heading
  - Electrotypes, 1929
  - Empire Film Vaults, 1929-1930
  - Employees
    - General, 1914-1925
    - Bonding, 1917-1919
    - Branch managers' life stories, 1916-1917 (Box 19)
    - Interoffice memoranda, 1917-1918
    - Lists
  - Endorsements
    - Deliverance, 1921-1926
    - Julius Caesar
      - 1912-1930, undated, (3 folders)
      - Printed matter
    - The Merchant of Venice, 1922
    - Pilgrim's Progress, 1922
    - Quo Vadis?, 1913
    - Spartacus, 1923-1928, undated
    - Miscellaneous, 1922-1926
  - Equipment theater, 1916-1925
  - Equitable Translation Service (Box 20)
  - Equity Building & Loan Association, 1929
  - Essanay Film Manufacturing Co., 1916-1927, undated
  - Evolutional system applicants
  - Exchanges, 1919-1921
  - Exhibitors
    - Advertising, 1916
    - Associations, 1916-1926
    - Europe, 1913
    - Sunday opening, 1919
  - Exhibitors' Film Co., 1919-1920 See also Container 21, same heading
  - Execution of Czolgosz, 1940
  - Exploitation and distribution
  - Eye strain and motion pictures
  - Famous Players-Lasky Corp. See Container 21; and 43, same heading
  - Farrell, E. J. See Container 34, Major Film Inc.
  - Fassini, Baron, 1928
  - Federal Securities Corp. See Container 21, same heading
  - Fifth Avenue Laundry, 1929
  - Fifth Avenue Playhouse, 1928
  - Film Arts Guild, 1928
  - Film Associates of California, 1928
  - Film Booking Offices of America, 1924
  - Film Bureau, 1927
  - Film Clearing House, 1918
  - Film Co. of Ireland See Container 63, Warde, Arthur F.
  - Film Daily, 1927-1928
  - Film Sales Co. See Container 54, Stone, Harry S.
  - Film Service Bureau (H.T. Collard), 1920-1921
  - Film title prices
  - Filmtab, Inc., 1929
  - Finances (Box 21)
    - Bankruptcies, 1920-1928
    - Deposits, 1916
    - Derr (A. C.) Co.
    - Exhibitors' Film Co.
    - Expenses, 1917-1923
    - Famous Players-Lasky Corp., 1917-1927
    - Federal Securities Corp., 1920
    - Film stock
    - Financialstic Debater, 1927, undated
    - Foreign market buyers
    - Griffith (D. W.) Inc.
    - Historical Film Corp., of America
    - Imperial Films, 1924-1927
    - Kleine attractions (key to expenses for branches), 1913-1919
    - Kleine Optical Co., 1903-[1917?]
    - Ledger (pages only), 1919-1922
    - Ledger (cast) book, 1924-1927
    - Ledger book, 1901-1928 (Box 22)
    - Little Picture House
    - Miscellaneous
    - Non-theatrical films, 1924-1925
    - Stock market, 1928-1930
    - Story rights cost
    - Theater construction, 1924-1928
  - Fires, 1917-1926 (Box 23)
  - First National Exhibitors' Circuit, 1920
  - First National Pictures, 1929 See also Container 49, First National Pictures and Unione Cinematographica Italiana
  - Flagg Comedies, 1919
  - Fleming, Grace (Mrs. Edward), 1927
  - Flu epidemic, 1918-1919
  - For Napoleon and France, 1914
  - For the Honor of the School, 1916-1917
  - Ford, Henry, 1921
  - Foreign films, 1913, undated
  - Foreign sales, 1921-1922
  - Foreign territory, 1921
  - Forms
  - France (Alfred Bourget), 1920-1927, undated, (4 folders)
  - Franklin Simon and Co., 1929
  - Frasso, Comte, Dentice, 1919
  - Friars Club, 1913-1917
  - Frohman, Milton C., 1929
  - Fulco Sales Co. See Container 61, same heading
  - Furmiss, Thomas, 1916
  - [Gallacher?], A. H., 1929 (Box 24)
  - Gallegher, 1922-1928
  - Gardner, Jack, 1930
  - Gaumont, 1909-1915, undated
  - Geddes, John J., 1921
  - Geller, James J.
  - General Electric Co., lecture service
  - General Film Co., 1910-[1920?], undated See also Container 26; and Container 33, same heading, (4 folders)
  - General Film Co. [Canada] See Container 9, Cooper, Thomas S.; and Container 5, Cooper, Thomas S., and Charles Berman
  - General Theatres Equipment, 1929-1930
  - Gibson, Miles T., 1917
  - Giffen, R. L. (Larry), 1919-1930
  - Gifford, F. W., 1915
  - Gilchrist, Emily (Mrs. William), 1917
  - Gillett Camera Stores, 1929
  - The Girl Alaska (Case of Soapy Smith), 1919, 1930
  - Globe Film Exchange See Container 36, same heading
  - Gloria's Romance (Randolph Corp.), 1915-1920
  - Glory of Clementine, 1927
  - Goldwyn Pictures Corp., 1920
  - Gordon (school), 1929
  - Gowen, Albert Y., 1921
  - Gradwell, Ricord (Producers Security Corp.), 1923-1924
  - Graham and Scott See Container 61, same heading
  - Gradin, Ethel See Container 53, Smallwood case
  - Grau, Robert, 1913-1915
  - Graves, Armgaard Karl, 1921-1928, undated
  - Great Meadow Prison, Comstock, N.Y., 1922 (Box 25)